In this lecture, we're going to learn about e-learning app architecture, the use case that we
discussed previously, and we're going to look at 10 key architecture considerations,
you need to think about to build production ready rag apps. So, this is the business use case
that we discussed previously. Now, let's take a look at the architecture.
The first we have the LNDT, which has the training documents, and they have to upload the documents
in some data source. So, that's the first choice you have to make, the data source and data type.
So, is it structured data, maybe in a relational database, or maybe it's in a data warehouse,
or is it unstructured data like PDF, images, videos, etc. And where are they going to reside?
So, are they on SharePoint, maybe an S3 bucket, or maybe they are in confluence as free text.
So, once you have identified the data source and data type, you have to transform the data
through data chunking. So, there are different type of data chunking strategies,
as we'll go along and discuss each of them in detail. So, there is no chunking,
fix size chunking, semantic chunking, hierarchy chunking. So, based on the use case,
you will need to identify what is the right chunking strategy for your use case.
So, before I continue, I just want to tell you that if you're not understanding some part of
this architecture, it's okay. We're going to deep dive into each of them in detail in the later
sections. So, once you have defined your data chunking strategy, then you have to create the
vector embeddings, and that is through the embedding model. So, you need to identify what's the
right embedding model. So, you have to evaluate the embedding model characteristics,
such as whether it's a multi-modal, does it only support text based, what are the vector size,
is it 512, 1024, number of languages, it supports, and whole lot of other parameters.
So, based on the use case, you need to select the right embedding model. So, once you have made
the decision, next is to select the right vector database. So, you'll store these vector embeddings.
So, there are a lot of different vector databases that AWS supports. So, your S3 vectors,
open search, pine cone, and each of them offer a different capability, and you have to identify the
right vector database based on your use case. And we're going to discuss this in a lot more detail,
but that's a decision you have to make while building your rack application.
Okay, now, this whole process is sometimes called as the ingestion pipeline,
and before the user actually starts querying, you have to build this ingestion pipeline.
Now, once we build this ingestion pipeline, now let's see how our e-learning app would actually work.
Now, we have an employee who poses a question through a chat interface, which says,
which bedrock model offers lowest latency and is approved in my organization. So, what's
going to happen is once he poses this question, it's going to pass through a text embedding model.
The text embedding model that you had selected here, so this question is going to pass through
that text embedding model, vector embeddings are going to be created, and then similarity search
is going to happen. And it's going to search for the relevant chunks in this vector database.
And then from this vector database, 5 to 20 chunks would be retrieve.
Now, the fifth option to optimize the retrieval accuracy is to use re-ranker model.
And I have a separate section on this re-ranker model later, but what re-ranker model is going to do
is based on the 5 to 20 retrieve chunks is going to reduce and re-rank all those chunks based on
the relevance to the user query. So, rather than sending out all the 20 chunks to the large
language model, it's going to re-rank the chunks based on relevance. So, then the chunk sometimes
call as the context along with the user question are sent to a large language model. So,
this is your sixth decision point where you need to select the right large language model for
your use case. So, once this large language model gets the context or the chunks and the user
question, it's going to generate an answer and send it back to the user. So, there are some
other architectural considerations you need to keep in mind. Like we previously discussed on the
model evaluation, so there is also a rag evaluation capability in Amazon bedrock that will help you
evaluate the response from your rag based application. So, then you also need to think about the
monitoring and observability. So, we're going to look at the different monitoring and observability
capabilities that cloud watch offers for rag based apps. And then finally, you have the security
and guard rails and responsible AI that you need to consider while building your rag based
application. So, we have two different sections on security and guard rails and responsible AI
in this course in the later sections. So, these are the 10 decision points you need to
think through from architecture perspective. And then for each decision point, you need to know
what are the various options and which option would be relevant for what kind of a use case.
And this is going to be tested in the exam and we're going to discuss all of these 10 in
lot more details. Okay. So, that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture.
Thank you.